ibsstl.org 2015-06-08

# Privacy Policy - Customers — Biblica

Please click here to view the terms of use page.

Biblica US, Inc., ("Biblica") has created this privacy statement to let businesses, consumers and the general public know how we collect and use the personal information you provide to us.

### Contact Information

To request a correction or deletion of your personal information, or if you have any questions and general comments about this privacy policy, please contact us at:

E-mail: [BiblicaDirectMail@biblica.com](mailto:biblicadirectmail@biblica.com)

Surface mailing address: Biblica, 1820 Jet Stream Drive, Colorado Spring, CO 80921

### What Information Do We Collect?

When visiting our web sites, you may provide us with two types of information, (i) personal information you voluntarily choose to disclose that is collected on an individual basis and, (ii) web site use information gathered on a collective basis as you and others browse our web site. Biblica does not collect personal information without your knowledge while you are visiting our website. The type of information we collect directly corresponds with the service you request. For instance, you can offer your thoughts, opinions, prayers, concerns, ideas, personal experiences, questions and/or suggestions to our articles or materials; or you can request that a resource be sent to you directly. The type of information we collect is only the information necessary to facilitate our response to your specific request such as your name and contact information. If you request to have a resource sent to you, Biblica will collect the information necessary to complete this transaction that may include your contact information, credit card number, and other transaction information. If you offer your thoughts, comments, opinions, concerns, ideas, personal experience testimonies, request prayer, ask questions, etc., Biblica collects that information and may use the information in one of the ways set forth in the following section titled "Use of Information."

### Use of Information

Biblica retains all rights to use the information provided by you to:

  * Respond to your correspondence, questions, comments, suggestions, thoughts, opinions, prayers, concerns, or ideas to fulfill a resource request.
  * Process your request for resources from our online resource services.
  * Continually update, develop, design, and customize the content of our website to meet the needs, interests and requests of our audience.
  * Contact you via e-mail to confirm specific resource or information requests, inform you of new products and special offers, or provide information we think may be of particular interest to you.

### With Whom Do We Share Information

We may share information about you with third parties in certain circumstances including in the following situations:

Affiliates. We may share all types of information with organizations that we own or control, or that own or control us.

Blogs, Online Postings, and Testimonials. We may share with the public any information that you publish in conjunction with an on-line review, comment, blog, or message board.

Transition. In the event that we, or part, or all, of our assets are acquired, we may share all types of information with the acquiring organization. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information,

Law Enforcement. We may report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we reasonably believe to be unlawful, or that we believe may aid a law enforcement investigation. In addition, we reserve the right to release all types of information to law enforcement agencies if we determine, in our sole judgment, that either you have violated our policies, or the release of information about you may protect the rights, property or safety of us or another person.

Legal Processes. We may share all types of information with others as required by, or permitted by, law. This may include sharing information with governmental entities, or third parties in response to subpoenas, court orders, other legal process, or as we believe is necessary to exercise our legal rights, to defend against legal claims that have been brought against us, or to defend against possible legal claims that we determine in our sole discretion might be brought against us.

Service Providers. We share information with people and companies that provide us with services. These services may include, among other things, helping us provide products or services that you request, create or maintain our databases, research or analyze the people who use our websites, or process payment card information. 

Alliances and Partnerships.  We may enter into alliances, partnerships or other arrangements with third parties who may be given access to your information, including your name and address, for the purpose of providing you information regarding products or services that we think may be of interest to you.

### What are "Cookies" and How Do We Use Information We Collect from them?

Our site uses cookies to differentiate you from other customers and to enhance your onsite experience by preventing repeated ads, or requiring you to log in more than is necessary for security. Cookies, in conjunction with our web server's log files, allow us to calculate the aggregate number of people visiting our web site and which parts of the site are most popular. This helps us gather feedback in order to constantly improve our web site and better serve our customers. Cookies do not allow us to gather any personal information about you and we do not generally store any personal information that you provided to us in your cookies. Cookies are considered industry standard. Your browser is probably set to accept cookies. If you choose to alter your browser to refuse cookies, it is possible some areas of our site will not function properly when you view them.

### Mail Preferences

Postal Mail: Biblica mails catalogs and other promotions to customers and prospective customers on a periodic basis. These catalogs highlight special offers and new product we believe will be of interest to our customers. If you wish to not receive these mailings, please let us know by emailing us at [BiblicaDirectMail@biblica.com](mailto:biblicadirectmail@biblica.com), calling us at **1-800-524-1588** , or writing us at **Biblica, 1820 Jet Stream Drive, Colorado Spring, CO 80921**.

Email: Biblica also communicates with our customers through email. An "unsubscribe" link is provided on every email we send. If you are receiving email from us and wish to stop receiving communication via email, simply click on the "unsubscribe" link provided and you will immediately and automatically cease receiving email promotions from us. A secondary way to unsubscribe from email communication is to go to "my account" on BiblicaDirect.com and change your email preferences.

Sharing mailing lists with third parties: Biblica may enter into alliances, partnerships or other arrangements with third parties who may be given access to contact information including your name and address, for the purpose of providing you information regarding products and services that we think may be of interest to you. Donor information is not shared in these arrangements. If you would prefer to not receive mailings from these organizations, please let us know by contacting us toll-free at 800-524-1588 or emailing us at [BiblicaDirectMail@biblica.com.](mailto:biblicadirectmail@biblica.com)

Donor information (such as name, address, e-mail address) that you entrust to Biblica is not shared with any third party without your permission to do so.

### How Do We Protect Your Information?

Email is not recognized as a secure medium of communication. For this reason, we request that you do not send private information to us by email. Some of the information you may enter on our web site may be transmitted securely via Secure Sockets Layer SSL, 128 bit encryption services. Pages utilizing this technology will have URLs that start with HTTPS instead of HTTP. Please contact [BiblicaDirectMail@biblica.com or call 1-800-524-1588 if you have any questions or concerns. ](mailto:biblicadirectmail@biblica.com)

### How Can You Access and Correct Your Information?

You may request access to all your personally identifiable information that we collect online and maintain in our database by contacting us at the above contact information.

Your California Privacy Rights. Under California Civil Code sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents who have an established relationship with us are entitled to ask us for a notice describing what categories of personal customer information we share with third parties or corporate affiliates for those third parties or corporate affiliates’ direct marketing purposes. That notice will identify the categories of information shared and will include a list of the third parties and affiliates with which it was shared, along with their names and addresses. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to the following address: [BiblicaDirectMail@biblica.com](mailto:biblicadirectmail@biblica.com) . Please allow 30 days for a response.

### What About Other Web Sites Linked to Our Web Site?

We are not responsible for the practices employed by web sites linked to or from our web site nor the information or content contained therein. Often links to other web sites are provided solely as pointers to information on topics that may be useful to the users of our web site. Please remember that when you use a link to go from our web site to another web site, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other web site, including web sites which have a link on our web site, is subject to that web site's own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding.

### Your Consent

By visiting and using our web site you consent to our collection and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on our web site to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it. At any time you may request to view any and all changes and updates, via surface mail.

### Notification of Changes

The Privacy Policy is subject to periodic review and change. In order to view the current Privacy Policy, simply check this section of the website. If we materially change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement and other places we deem appropriate so users are aware of what information we collect, how it is used, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. In some cases when we post a notice, we may also email users who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.

### How Do We Communicate With You

If we need, or are required, to contact you concerning any event that involves information about you we may do so by email, telephone, or mail.
